今日 初めて観る人もいるかも…｡
各自 勝手に ついてきてれば！
(神楽)いいかげん 飽きたｱﾙ｡
えっ？ だって➡
(神楽)習うより なめろｱﾙ｡
なめて どうすんだよ！ なめて!!
(銀時)つうか もう いいだろ？
そのﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ｡
いいんだよ｡ どうせ 説明しても
よくわかんねえ世界なんだから｡
(新八)＜侍の国｡ ﾎﾞｸらの国が
そう呼ばれたのは 今は 昔の話＞
The land of the samurai.
There was a time, long ago, when our country was called by that name.
With the arrival of the "Amanto" from outer space...
Can't we skip this intro already?
I'm getting really sick of it.
Huh? But there might be people watching this for the first time.
Don't bother.
It's a world they wouldn't understand even if we explained it, anyway.
They can follow along at their own pace.
Don't learn it, taste it.
What good is tasting it gonna do?!
[The Client: Taizo Hasegawa, Chief of Foreign Bureau Department. ]
[He's an important Ju-chin in the government. When we say Chin, we don't mean that kind of Chin.]
(ﾊﾀ皇子)ううっ… ﾍﾟｽ… ﾍﾟｽ～!!
(長谷川)申し訳ありません｡
I am very sorry.
(長谷川)手を尽くして
捜したのですが 発見できません｡
We looked everywhere, but we were unable to find him.
It appears he is no longer within these grounds.
(長谷川)どうやら この敷地内には
いないようです｡
(じい)ふざけんじゃねえ!!
Don't be ridiculous!
(局員)局長！
Chief!
いませんでしたじゃ
済まねえだろうが！
"Not here" isn't good enough!
(長谷川)し… しかし…｡
(じい)口答えは いらねえんだよ！
B-But...
I don't need your back talk.
You Edo officials just have to do our bidding!
(じい)ｵﾒｴら 江戸の役人は➡
ｵﾚらの望みを
叶えてりゃいいんだ！
どんな手え使ってでも 捜し出せ
ｵﾗ～!!
Use whatever means necessary to find him!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)ﾍﾟｽ～！ ﾍﾟｽ～!!
(じい)
わかったら さっさと行けや！
You heard me-now get moving!
(長谷川)はい… すみません…｡
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
(局員)局長… 上層部に
このことが漏れるのだけは➡
Chief!
We must prevent word of this from leaking to the upper echelons.
阻止しませんと…｡
(長谷川)…あぁ 手は考えてある｡
I know. I have a plan.
Hey there! You useless naturally wavy haired lout!
(お登勢)ｺﾗ～！ 能なし天然ﾊﾟｰﾏ!!
(お登勢)今日こそ
たまってる家賃➡
Today I'm making you pay every penny of the back rent you've piled up!
耳を揃えて
ｷｯﾁﾘ払ってもらうからね～!!
あ～ わかった わかった｡
Yeah, I heard you, I heard you.
しようがねえな～｡ ほらよ｡
Guess I don't have a choice.
Here.
ｱﾃﾞｨｵｽ｡
Adios.
♪♪～
Hey, what's with the 230 yen?
ｺﾗ！ なにが 230円だよ!!
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣と勘違いしてんじゃねえぞ
ｸｿｶﾞｷ～!!
You're not buying JUMP, you know! Worthless punk!
ねえんだよ！
それしか ねえんだよ!!
I don't have it!
That's all I've got!
それくらい察しろ 鈍感女！
Try to understand at least that much, you clueless old bat!
金が ねえなら
金持ちのﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ ひとりや ふたり➡
If you don't have money, go swindle an old lady or two.
たぶらかしてこい！
この ﾀﾏなし天然ﾊﾟｰﾏ!!
Ain'tcha got any balls, curly?
いつまでも 金 金 金 金
ちっちぇこと言ってんじゃねえ！
Always going on and on about petty things like money, money, money!
ﾃﾒｴが たぶらかされてえなら
そう言え｡ 欲求不満ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ！
If you wanna be seduced, just say so, you starved slut!
(お登勢)ｱﾀｼが欲しいんなら
ﾊﾅから そう言えや！
What?! If you want me, you should've said so from the start!
ｵｴｯ！ ｹﾞﾛ吐かせてえなら
遠慮なく吐くぞ～｡
If you're tryin' to make me puke, I'd be happy to oblige you!
今週も ｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞから 苦情殺到…!?
(局員)局長 あそこです｡
You want a flood of complaints from the very start of this episode, too?
Chief, that's the place.
(お登勢)いいかい？
あと １日だけ待ってやる｡
Hmph! Look, I'll wait just one more day!
(お登勢)
それで払えないんだったら➡
If you still can't pay, you're outta here. I'm serious!
ﾏｼﾞ 出ていってもらうからね～！
(長谷川)…行くぞ｡
Let's go.
["Responsible Owners Should Clean Up After Their Pets"]
What're you going to do?
どうすんすか？ ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣買う
230円まで持ってかれて…｡
She even took the 230 yen that you were going to spend on JUMP.
今月の ﾎﾞｸの給料
出るんでしょうね？ 頼みますよ｡
You'll be able to pay me this month's wages, won't you?
I'm counting on you. My household budget is already smelling bad as it is.
ﾎﾞｸんちの家計だって
きついんだから…｡
(神楽)満員電車の
おじさんのお口も きついｱﾙ｡
So is the breath of all those old guys packed onto the trains.
新八｡
はい？
Shinpachi?
Yes?
お前 彼女 いなかったっけ？
なんすか？ いきなり…｡
You don't have a girlfriend, right?
What's with this, all of a sudden?
年上の女性と つきあう気な～い？
Interested in going out with an older woman?
お登勢 って言うんだけど！
んっ？
Her name's Otose.
((ｳｯﾌﾝ！))
あぁぁ～っ!!
Who the hell would go out with her!
つきあうか～!! つうか 人の青春
なんだと思ってんだよ～!!
And what do you take a person's youth for?!
ｶﾘｺﾘすんなや｡
Don't get your panties bunched up.
金はな がっつくﾔﾂのところには
入ってこねえもんさ｡
Money doesn't come to guys who really want it.
見た目 さわやかで 人に➡
It comes to people who appear cool, and cause mayhem.
苦労させようとするﾔﾂのところに
入ってくるｱﾙ｡
それって ｱﾝﾀらだよ！
That would be you two!
Just you guys alone would make anyone's indecisiveness go away!
ｱﾝﾀらだけで
決定力不足 解消だよ!!
あり？ 映り悪いな｡
Huh? Tube's on the fritz.
おっ 入った｡
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)現場の 結野さん｡
Oh, it's coming in.
Ketsuno is on the scene. Ms. Ketsuno?
結野ｱﾅ～！
(結野ｱﾅ)はい｡
Yes, this is Ketsuno reporting from the scene.
こちら 現場の 結野です｡
It appears that the mysterious giant organism
大江戸温泉に現れた
謎の巨大生物は➡
数時間もの間
周辺の施設を破壊し➡
that appeared at Oedo Hot Spa and destroyed facilities in the area,
突如 姿を消した模様です｡
over the course of several hours, has disappeared.
Hey, hey... Another alien got out of the terminal, eh?
おいおい
また ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙから ｴｲﾘｱﾝ侵入か？
最近 多いｱﾙね｡
Quite a few, recently.
ｴｲﾘｱﾝより 今は どうやって➡
More than the alien, the bigger problem is how are we going to make a living.
生計立てるかのほうが
問題ですよ｡
(玄関のﾁｬｲﾑ)
ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ…！
That old hag.
金なら もう ねえって
言ってんだろうが！ 腐れﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ!!
If it's about the money, I already told you I don't have any! You rotten hag!
(長谷川)ｸﾞﾌｯ…｡
あれ？
Huh?
Chief!
(局員)局長～!?
貴様！ 何をするか!!
Damn you! What do you think you're doing?!
Sorry about that. My mistake. I'll come back another time.
すんません！ 間違えました｡
出直します｡
(局員)待て～っ！
Hold it!
♪♪～
You're the Odd Jobs man, aren't you? Come with us.
(局員)貴様が 万事屋だな？
我々と一緒に 来てもらおう｡
悪いな｡ 知らねえ人には
ついていくな って➡
Sorry. Mom told me not go with strangers.
母ちゃんに言われてんだ｡
Didn't you learn not to disobey the law?
御上の言うことには
逆らうな とは➡
教わらなかったか？
ｵﾒｴら 幕府の…？
You're...with the government?
入国管理局の者だ｡
We're with the Immigration Bureau.
ｱﾝﾀに 仕事の依頼にきた｡
万事屋さん｡
We came to hire you for a job, Mr. Odd Jobs.
入国管理局の
長谷川 泰三っていったら➡
When you say Taizo Hasegawa of the Immigration Bureau,
天人の 出入国の一切を
取り締まってる➡
you're talking about that big shot government official who oversees all Amanto immigration?
幕府の重鎮ですよ｡
A big shot? Does that mean he has a big schlong?
ｼﾞｭｳﾁﾝ って 10個のﾁﾝﾁﾝｱﾙか？
ｹﾀﾞﾓﾉのﾁﾝだ｡
A beastly one.
いや 重要な人 ってことね…｡
っていうか 神楽ちゃん➡
No, it means he's an important government official.
And Kagura, a girl shouldn't be saying such things.
女の子が そんなこと言っちゃ
ﾀﾞﾒでしょ？
とにかく そんな幕府の大物が
いったい 何の用でしょう？
At any rate, what does a government bigwig want with us?
何の用ですか？ 重鎮さん｡
What do you want, Mr. Big Schlong?
万事屋つったっけ？
金さえ積めば➡
Odd Jobs, was it?
I heard there were people who would do anything if I piled on the money.
何でもやってくれるﾔﾂがいる って
聞いてさ｡
ちょっと 仕事を頼みたくてね｡
I've come to ask you to do a job.
A job? Are you guys doing yours?
仕事だ～？
ﾃﾒｴら 仕事なんてしてたのか？
街 見てみろ｡
天人どもが 好き勝手やってるぜ？
Look around town. The Amanto are doing whatever they please.
(長谷川)こりゃ 手厳しいね｡
That was harsh. We're doing all we can, you know.
(長谷川)ｵﾚたちも
やれることは やってんだがね…｡
♪♪～
(長谷川)なんせ 江戸が
これだけ進歩したのも➡
After all, Edo's developed this far thanks to them, you know.
ﾔﾂらの おかげだからな｡
(長谷川)おまけに ここを
えらく 気に入っているようだし➡
And plus, they seem to really like this place.
無下には扱えんだろう｡
So we can't treat them badly now, can we?
(長谷川)すでに 幕府の中枢にも
天人は 根を張ってるしな｡
And the Amanto already have their networks rooted in the heart of the government.
(長谷川)地球から
ﾔﾂらを追い出そうなんて夢は➡
We have to stop dreaming that we can drive them off of the Earth.
もう 見んことだ…｡
ｵﾚたちにできることは➡
All we can do is to try to coexist with them.
ﾔﾂらと うまいこと
共生していくことだけだよ｡
ふ～ん 共生ねえ…｡
Hmm...coexist, eh?
お前 そんなことやってて
楽しいわけ？
And you enjoy doing that?
♪♪～
まぁ いいや｡
んで ｵﾚたちに どうしろっての？
Well, never mind. So, what do you want us to do?
ん？ あぁ…｡
(長谷川)ｵﾚたちも あまり
ﾊﾃﾞに動けん仕事でな｡
It's a job we can't move on very openly.
(長谷川)公にすると
幕府の信用が落ちかねん｡
If it becomes public, the government will lose face.
…実はな 今 幕府は
外交上の問題で➡
The fact is the government is in a diplomatic crisis
that could have a decisive influence on our country.
国を 左右するほどの
危機を迎えてるんだ｡
(長谷川)央国星の皇子が
ここに滞在しているんだが➡
The prince of the Midland Star is staying here...
その皇子が
ちょっと 問題を抱えていてな…｡
And the prince has a problem...
(ﾊﾀ皇子)余のﾍﾟｯﾄの ﾍﾟｽがのぅ
いなくなってしまったのじゃ｡
My pet, Pesu, has disappeared...
(ﾊﾀ皇子)捜し出して
捕らえてくれんかのぅ？
Might I ask you to collect him for me?
おい～！ ちょっと待て～!!
Hey! Hold on!
ｷﾐら 万事屋だろ!?
何でもやる 万事屋だろ!?
You guys do Odd Jobs right?! You'll do anything, right?
いや わかるよ！
わかるけど やって！
No, I know! I know, but take the job! Please!
頼むから やって～!!
Shut up or I'll break your shades, Baldy.
うるせえな ｸﾞﾗｻﾝ｡
たたき割るぞ うすらﾊｹﾞ｡
ﾋｹﾞ むしるぞ この野郎！
(長谷川)ﾊｹﾞでいい！
I'll yank off your beard, bastard!
Go ahead, call me baldy.
(長谷川)ﾋｹﾞ むしってもいいから
やってくれ！
You can yank off my beard, too, but just take the job!
ﾔﾊﾞｲんだよ｡ あそこの国からは➡
We're in a bind here.
The government borrowed quite a bit of money from his country.
いろいろ 金とかも借りてるから
ｳﾁの幕府…｡
知らねえよ｡ そっちの問題だろ？
What do we care? It's your problem.
ﾍﾟｯﾄくらいで滅ぶ国なら
滅んだほうがいいわ｡
If the country's gonna collapse just because of a stupid a pet,
then it should go ahead and collapse.
ﾍﾟｯﾄくらいとは なんじゃ｡
ﾍﾟｽは 余の 家族同然ぞ｡
What do you mean by "just a pet"?
Pesu is like family.
だったら ﾃﾒｴで捜してください
ﾊﾞｶ皇子！
Then please look for it yourself. Prince Pinhead.
おい～!! ﾊﾞｶだけど 皇子だから！
皇子なの～!!
Hey! He's a pinhead, but he's still a prince. A prince!
出てったﾔﾂのことなんか忘れて➡
Forget the one who leaves you, and prepare for a new love.
新たな 恋の準備するのが
今どきの 強い女ｱﾙ！
That's what a strong woman of today would do.
ﾌﾗれてないし 女でもないから！
He wasn't jilted, and it wasn't a woman!
ﾊﾞｶだけど 皇子だから これ！
ﾊﾞｶだけど!!
He's a pinhead, but he's a prince! He's a pinhead, but...
わかってますよ｡
ﾊﾞｶだけど 皇子なんでしょ？
We understand. He's a pinhead, but he's a prince, right?
(長谷川)そう！ ﾊﾞｶだけど 皇子!!
(神楽)そうか！
That's right. A pinhead, but a prince!
I get it. A pinhead, but a prince, eh?
(神楽)ﾊﾞｶだけど 皇子ｱﾙか！
それって ﾊﾞｶ皇子 ってことだろ？
In other words, he's a pinhead prince?
(長谷川)違うから！
ﾊﾞｶだけど 皇子だから!!
No, he's a pinhead, but a prince.
貴様ら～!! ﾊﾞｶﾊﾞｶって
ﾊﾞｶ皇子に 失礼であるぞ！
You keep calling him a pinhead.
That's very disrespectful to the pinhead Prince!
…って お前も ﾊﾞｶつけてんじゃん｡
You just called me a pinhead, as well.
大体 そんな問題➡
Can't you handle a problem like that by yourselves?
あなたたちだけで
解決できるでしょう？
うっ…｡ まぁ こっちはこっちで
いろいろあってな…｡
Well... We have our reasons...
これくらいのこと
万事屋さんなら 問題ねえだろ？
It'd be no problem for Mr. Odd Jobs, right?
いや｡ いくら 万事屋といってもな
御上に ｼｯﾎﾟ振って➡
No. We may be called Odd Jobs,
but we haven't lost sight of ourselves to the point where we would wag our tails for the government
お偉い様の くだらねえ
使いっぱしりさせられるほど➡
自分を 見失っちゃいねえ…｡
いくぞ 新八 神楽｡
and do their errands for them.
Let's go, Shinpachi. Kagura.
じゃあな ｼﾞｭｳﾁﾝ！
See ya, Big Schlong.
ちなみに 謝礼は たっぷり
払わせてもらうつもりだがな｡
Just so you know, we intended to compensate you very generously.
で どうすればいいんですか？
So, what do we have to do?
ご主人様
何でも言ってくださいｱﾙ！
Yes, Boss, we'll do anything you say!
早すぎるよ！
もうちょっと 悩もうよ!!
That was quick! Let's mull this over a bit more!
(長谷川)捜してほしいのは
この ﾍﾟｽというﾀｺみたいなｴｲﾘｱﾝだ｡
What I want you to find is this octopus-like alien named Pesu.
(長谷川)おそらく
街を うろついている｡
It's probably wandering around the city.
(長谷川)とにかく
今日中に生け捕って➡
Anyway, I want you to capture it alive and bring it back here today.
無傷で ここに連れてきてくれ｡
Just because Pesu is like an octopus, would it be in the harbor?
いくら ﾍﾟｽが ﾀｺっぽいからって
港なんかに いるんですかね？
いいんだよ｡ 何でもいいから
ひとつ ｷｯｶｹをつかんで➡
It doesn't matter. It can be anything.
All we need is one lead, and we can go from there.
そこから 切り崩すんだ｡
It works at speed-dating parties.
合ｺﾝでも 有効な手ｱﾙ｡
ん？ ﾀｺ壺…｡
Hey, octopus jars.
あれを その辺に仕掛けて
待ってたら どうですか？
What if we set them in that area and wait?
あぁ～ん？
告白できない 中学生ですか？
Huh? Are you some teenager who can't confess his affections?
待ってるだけじゃ
恋も ﾀｺ捜しも 成就しねえの！
Waiting doesn't get you love or help you find an octopus.
くだらねえこと言ってないで
行くぞ！
Stop this useless talk. Let's go.
Hmm. I know a lot about sea octopuses, but I don't know anything about land octopuses.
(漁師)う～ん｡ 海のﾀｺなら
よく知ってるが➡
陸のﾀｺだと
ちと わからねえなぁ…｡
(漁師)陸の ﾀｺ屋に聞いてみれば？
Why not ask a shop that sells land octopuses?
(ﾀｺ焼き屋の男)ﾀｺは
いろいろ見てきたけどよ➡
I've seen many kinds of octopuses,
こんなﾂﾗ 知らねえなぁ｡
but never one that looks like this.
おう ｻﾌﾞ｡ ｵﾒｴ このﾂﾗ
見たことあるかい？
Hey, Sabu. Ever seen one that looks like this?
Yeah.
(ｻﾌﾞ)あぁ…｡ 表通りのｽﾅｯｸに
たしか こんなｺが…｡
I think I saw a small one like that at the shop on the main street.
(ｳﾞｧﾈｯｻ)で？ ｱﾀｼに 何の用？
So, did you want something?
(２人)ﾍﾟｽだ～！
惜しいけど 違うでしょ～!!
It's Pesu!
Close, but no cigar!
いや なんかさ
この 目のあたりとか似てない？
No, don't you think they look kinda similar here around the eyes?
ｷﾐ お父さん似？
ﾏﾏ似ｱﾙね？
Do you look like your father?
Maybe your mother?
違うから！ 一応 人だから!!
No! She's a human being!
っていうか お前ら
全員 ﾊﾞｶにしてんの？
Are you people making fun of me?
よし わかった｡
お前は 今日から ﾍﾟｽだ｡
Okay, I've got it. From today, you'll be Pesu.
はぁ!? ｱﾀｼ ｳﾞｧﾈｯｻだから！
Huh? I'm Vanessa!
よし 今日から お前は
ｳﾞｧﾈｯｻ と言う名の ﾍﾟｽｱﾙ｡
Okay, from today, you'll be Pesu Vanessa.
普通の ｳﾞｧﾈｯｻでいいから！
Just plain Vanessa if fine!
まぁ とりあえず
一緒に来てくれよ｡
Anyway, please come with us.
We're supposed to be looking for an alien octopus!
だから
連れていかなきゃいけないのは➡
ｴｲﾘｱﾝの ﾀｺだってば！
ｴｲﾘｱﾝのﾀｺ？
Alien octopus?
えっ？ 知ってるんですか？
Huh? You know one?
(ｳﾞｧﾈｯｻ)そういえば さっき
ﾀｺみたいな 野良ｴｲﾘｱﾝを➡
Now that you mention it,
a girl who works here said that a stray octopus-alien was caught by the Humane Society.
保健所が 捕まえてた って
言ってたなぁ…➡
店の子が…｡
(神楽/銀時)ん？
ん？ あれは…！
That's...
いくぞ 新八！ 神楽!!
はい！
Let's go, Shinpachi. Kagura.
Right.
(神楽)じゃあな ﾍﾟｽもどき！
いや ｳﾞｧﾈｯｻだから！
See ya, Pesu look-a-like.
No, I'm Vanessa!
Gin, step on it or we won't catch up.
銀さん！ もっと急がないと
追いつかないよ!!
心配すんな！ 追われるより
追うほうが楽しいから➡
No worries. It's more fun to chase than be chased.
恋に恋して
少女は 大人になっていくんだ～!!
That's why young girls grow up to be adults by falling in love with love.
There!
(神楽)いたｱﾙ！
いくぜ～！
Let's go!
うぉぉ～っ!!
(新八と 神楽の悲鳴)
(３人)えっ!?
ちょっ ちょっと～!!
Hey, w-wait!
(激突音と 銀時たちの悲鳴)
ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃﾃﾃ…｡
Ow, ow, ow...
ん？ ｳﾌﾟｯ…！
…って これ ｲｶじゃん｡
It's a squid.
Listen, this is just like going after a delicate young girl with a broken heart.
いいか？ 追われてるﾔﾂってのは
失恋したての乙女並みに ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄだ｡
深追いは いかん！
We mustn't chase after it too far.
(神楽)やさぐれた 10代のﾊｰﾄも
とても ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄｱﾙ｡
The heart of a teen that runs away from home is also delicate.
大人たちは
何も わかってないｱﾙよ｡
Adults don't understand anything.
っていうか 銀さん…➡
Gin?
さんざん捜して
結局 ﾀｺ壺じゃないすか…｡
After all the searching we did, we've come back to the octopus jars...
ﾀｺは 壺の中が好きだからな…｡
Octopuses like being in jars.
(神楽)壺の中なんて
普通 死ななきゃ入れないｱﾙ｡
Normally, you have to die before they put you in a jar.
それ 骨壺だから…｡
You're talking about urns for ashes.
つうか 銀さん！ このｱｲﾃﾞｱ 最初に
ﾎﾞｸが言ったﾔﾂじゃないですか！
Gin, I was trying to tell you about this idea right from the start.
微妙に違うんだな…｡
It's just a tad different, I'd say.
｢捜してﾀﾞﾒなら
のんびりと待とう ﾎﾄﾄｷﾞｽ｣｡
If searching around doesn't work, we just wait patiently.
捜すの 面倒になっただけじゃん!!
You just got tired of searching!
あんなに あちこち捜して
結局 ﾀﾞﾒだったのに➡
After running around all over the place, will this really work?
今さら こんなんで
大丈夫ですかね…？
大丈夫さ｡ まぁ その…
え～と…　あれだ…➡
It'll work out. Well...er...uh... It will work out, right?
大丈夫だよな？
Do you know the meaning of the word "responsibility"?
あなた ｢責任｣って言葉
知ってますか？
(神楽)男が これだと
愛した女は いずれ 去っていくよ｡
Guys like you always end up getting dumped.
まぁ 心配すんな｡
甘く ささやきゃ➡
Don't worry.
Give them some sweet talk, and any woman or any octopus will come wagging their tail.
ﾀｺでも 女でも
ｼｯﾎﾟ振って やってくる｡
(神楽)女に ｼｯﾎﾟはないよ｡
Women don't have tails.
ﾀｺにも ねえだろ｡
自分で言ったんだろ!!
Neither do octopuses.
You were the one who said that!
あっ… いっ…？
ｳｿ～!? ﾎﾝﾄに 来た～～っ!!
I don't believe it! He really fell for it!
え～と… どちらさん？
ｳﾞｧﾈｯｻ？
Um...and who might you be?
Vanessa?
違えよ!! ﾍﾟｽですよ ﾍﾟｽ!!
No, it's not! It's Pesu. Pesu!
(神楽/銀時)ﾍﾟｽ～!?
Pesu?
Get him!
(銀時/神楽)捕まえろ～!!
Stop, you!
(３人)待て ｺﾗ～!!
(３人)ふぬ～っ！ ふぬ～っ!!
Hey! Stop shaking!
おい 揺らすな！
彼氏に 冷たくされたあと➡
You're not some young girl
他の男に 優しくされた
乙女心じゃねえんだぞ！
scorned by her boyfriend and treated gently by another man, you know!
In that case, the second guy has all the advantages!
(神楽)その状況だと
２番手の男のほうが 断然 有利ｱﾙ｡
この状況だと ﾍﾟｽを追いかけるのが
先決でしょう!!
In this case, our priority is to chase after Pesu!
(３人)ｲﾀ～ｯ！
Now what?! We can't get out!
どうすんすか！
抜けないじゃ～ん!!
あ～ もう
このまま 転がっちまえ～!!
Fine! Let's just roll around like this.
(悲鳴)
ｳｿ～っ!! …えっ？
何か これ ﾃﾞｼﾞｬﾌﾞｱﾙ！
Whoa, déjà vu!
早っ！ ﾍﾟｽ 早っ！
これじゃ 追いつかないってば～!!
He's fast! Pesu is fast! We'll never catch him like this!
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！ 走り出した思いは
誰にも止めらねえんだよ!!
Idiots! Once your feelings start to run, there's no stopping them.
これで 捕まえられなかったら
金持ちﾊﾞﾊﾞｱと つきあえや 新八！
If we don't catch him you get to date some rich old hag, Shinpachi, you fool!
この野郎～！
(神楽)人妻は熱いぞ この野郎～！
Wives are passionate, stupid!
Why is this my fault?!
っていうか なんで
ﾎﾞｸの責任なんすか!?
あぁっ…｡ 危ねえ!!
Look out!
(激突音と 悲鳴)
ｲｯﾃ～｡
Ouch!
あぁ～っ!!
潰しちゃったよ ちょっと～!!
We squished it!
さ… 騒ぐんじゃねえよ｡
Ch-Ch-Chill out and help me find a t-t-time machine.
とりあえず 落ち着いて
ﾀﾀﾀ… ﾀｲﾑﾏｼﾝ 探そう…｡
You chill out! And that again?!
ｱﾝﾀが 落ち着け～!!
って また それかい！
あ～あ…｡
Sorry to keep you waiting. Here's what you asked for.
待たせたな｡ ご注文の品だ｡
Oh...Pesu!
あぁ～っ!! ﾍﾟｽ～!!
…って これ 死んでんじゃん！
That thing is dead!
無傷どころか 顔の色
変わっちまってるよ！
It's not even damage-free, the face has changed color!
大丈夫だ｡ 化粧をしてみたくなる
年頃なだけだ｡
It's all right. It's just at that age when it wants to wear makeup.
思春期には よくある！
Happens a lot during adolescence.
壺で踏み潰されただけで
こんなんなっちゃって➡
All we did was flatten it with a jar and it turned out like this.
What a weakling!
ﾎﾝﾄ 弱っちいﾔﾂ…｡
潰したってか!?
ｵﾒｴらが やったってか!?
Flattened it?! You did this?!
まだ 死んでねえってば！
It's not dead yet! Just, barely alive.
虫の息だけど｡
虫の息なのが いかんっつうの!!
"Just barely alive" is the problem!
無傷でないのはともかく➡
Leaving aside the fact that it isn't unharmed...
とりあえず これ以上
被害が 拡大しなかったのは➡
We should be thankful the damage was not any worse than this.
不幸中の幸いだったな｡
被害？ どういうことですか？
Damage? What do you mean?
あれの もと いた 惑星の海は
温度が高くてな➡
The seas on the planet where that thing came from are very warm.
ﾍﾟｽは お湯をかけると
もとの大きさに戻ってしまうのだ｡
Pouring hot water on it will return Pesu to its original size.
お湯？ あっ…｡
Hot water?
(じい)わぁ～っ!!
なにやってんだ お前～!!
What're you doing?!
ﾌｩ～！ ﾌｩ～！ 茹でﾀﾞｺｱﾙ!!
Boiled octopus, uh-huh!
どどどど… どういうつもりだ～!?
Wh-wh-what are you thinking?!
おいしく食べてあげるのが
最高の供養ｱﾙよ｡
Enjoying it in a delicious manner is the ultimate memorial service!
Oh, it's boiled just right.
(神楽)おっ うまく
茹であがってきたｱﾙ｡
ﾊﾞ… ﾊﾞｶ野郎…｡
Y-You idiot.
ﾍﾟ… ﾍﾟｽ～!?
P-Pesu?!
No waaaay!
ｳｿ～～っ!?
言ったじゃん！
今 言ったばっかじゃん!!
Didn't you hear what he just said?!
ﾍﾟｽが…
ﾍﾟｽが よみがえったぞよ～！
Pesu! Pesu's come back to life!
Yahoo!
(神楽)お腹いっぱい
食べられるｱﾙ～！
I can eat my fill!
See, look! It's alive!
ほ～ら見ろ｡
生きてたじゃねえか！
(長谷川)この状況で 威張んな！
As if you had anything to be proud of!
(ﾍﾟｽの 雄たけび)
お～っ！ なかなか やるｱﾙね!!
Whoa.  It's pretty strong.
ﾃﾞｶくなるなんて
言ってなかったじゃないですか！
You never told us it would grow like that!
言ってないよ｡ 聞かれてないもん｡
I didn't tell you, because you didn't ask!
ちょっと ｱﾀｼ
あのｸｿｶﾞｷ 黙らしてくるｱﾙよ！
Give me a second. I'll shut that punk up!
Hold on.
(長谷川)おっと｡
勝手なﾏﾈは しないでもらおう｡
Don't do anything on your own.
これ以上 ｱｲﾂを傷つけるな｡
Don't injure it more than you already have.
Oh, I remember now!
ああっ！ 思い出した！
Is this that weird creature we saw going on a rampage on TV?!
ﾃﾚﾋﾞで暴れてた
謎の生物って これ!?
こんなん どうやって
捕まえるんすか!?
How're we supposed to capture something like this?!
っていうか
どうやって 飼ってたわけ？
For that matter, how were you keeping it?!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)ﾍﾟｽはのぅ➡
Pesu is an unknown organism discovered on a remote planet.
秘境の星で発見した
未確認生物でな➡
余に なついてしまったゆえ
船で牽引して➡
He became attached to me, so I led him back to my ship!
連れてかえって…｡
(ﾍﾟｽの 雄たけび)
He's not attached to you at all!
全然 なついてねえ!!
It must be low on calcium.
ｶﾙｼｳﾑ 足りてないｱﾙ…｡
(雄たけび)
Oh no! It's headed for the city again!
ﾔﾊﾞｲ！ また 市街に出る！
♪♪～
銀さん！
Gin!
Oh brother.
しようがねえなぁ…｡
神楽 醤油 買ってこい｡
今日の晩ごはんは ﾀｺの刺身だ！
Kagura, go buy some soy sauce.
We're having octopus sashimi for dinner tonight.
わかった！ 醤油ｱﾙね!!
Gotcha. Soy sauce, it is! We're feasting tonight!
今日は ごちそうｱﾙ!!
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ…｡
No, maybe takoyaki sounds better.
いや ﾀｺ焼きのほうがいいか…｡
It's lunchtime!
いただきま～す!!
(長谷川)させるか～!!
Forget it!
うぉぉ～～っ!! ｲﾀﾀﾀﾀﾀ…｡
Ow, ow, ow!
なに しやがんだ…｡
脳みそ 出てない？ これ｡
What was that for?! Is that my brain leaking out?
手え出しちゃ ﾀﾞﾒだ！
You mustn't hurt it! The prince told us to capture it unharmed!
無傷で捕まえろ って
皇子に言われてんだってば！
無傷？ できるか そんな～！
Unharmed?! Is that even possible?
それを なんとかしてもらおうと
ｱﾝﾀたち 呼んだの！
That's why I hired you! Now make it happen!
無理無理！ 無理だって～!!
(新八の悲鳴)
No way, no way. I'm telling you, no way!
Gin!
銀さ～ん!!
Shinpachi!
新八！ あっ…｡
(長谷川)勝手なﾏﾈするな って
言ってるでしょう？
I told you not to hurt it!
食われる～!!
ﾃﾒｴ…｡
Help! It's going to eat me!
Why you!
無傷で捕獲なんざ
不可能なのは 百も承知だよ｡
I knew perfectly well that capturing it unharmed was impossible.
多少の犠牲が出なきゃ
ﾊﾞｶ皇子は わかんないんだって｡
That pinhead prince won't get the message until the body count goes up a bit.
Hey! Are you listening to me?!
ちょっと～！ 聞いてんの～!?
あれの処分許可 得るために
ｳﾁの助手 ｴｻにするってか…｡
So you're using my sidekick as pet food to get permission to kill that thing?
You guys are rotten to the core.
どうやら ﾃﾒｴら
ﾎﾝﾄに腐っちまってるみてえだな｡
言ったろ？ ｵﾚたちは➡
I told you.
We have no choice but to coexist with them.
ﾔﾂらと 共生していくしか
ないんだってば｡
腐ってようが ｵﾚは ｵﾚのやり方で
国を守らせてもらう｡
Corrupt or not, I'm going to protect the country my way.
それが ｵﾚなりの武士道だ｡
That's my bushido.
ﾌｯ… そうかい｡
I see.
じゃあ ｵﾚは ｵﾚの武士道で
いかせてもらう!!
Then, I'm gonna follow my bushido, too!
Wait!
待て～!!
It's one human being versus a whole nation.
(長谷川)たった 一人の人間と
一国と➡
どっちが大事か 考えろ!!
Think about which is more important!
I don't give a damn about that!
知ったこっちゃねえな
んなこと～!!
だぁぁ～っ！ 新八～!!
Shinpachi!
気張れ～～っ!!
Hold on!
Hold on, he says.
気張れ ったって…｡
どﾁｸｼｮｳ～～っ!!
Damn it!
幕府が滅ぼうが
国が滅ぼうが 関係ねえ！
It doesn't matter whether the government collapses or the nation collapses!
ｵﾚは… 自分の肉体が滅ぶまで
背筋伸ばして 生きてくだけよ～!!
Until my body collapses, I will live my life standing tall!
Gin, your soy sauce!
銀ちゃん 醤油！
(うめき声)
《…あ～あ｡
Oh brother. That bastard's ruining everything!
ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬ やってくれやがって
あの野郎…》
あぁ～っ！ ﾍﾟｽが～!!
Ohhh, Pesu! My precious Pesu!
余の かわいいﾍﾟｽが～!!
It's like a fountain.
まるで 噴水のようじゃ～!!
(崩れ落ちる音)
Hasegawa! What's the meaning of this?!
(じい)長谷川！ どういうことだ!?
I told you to capture him unharmed!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)
無傷で捕らえよと 申した…！
どう 責任とってくれるか！
How will you take responsibility for this? It's an international incident!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)国際問題じゃ これは！
(じい)おい！ 聞いてんのか ﾃﾒｴ!!
Hey! Are you listening, damn it?!
Live standing tall?
《背筋を伸ばして生きる？
まるで ｶﾞｷの学級目標じゃねえか｡
It's almost like the goals a kid sets in grade school.
そういや おふくろも
よく言ってたなぁ…｡
Come to think of it, Mom always used to tell me.
You're slouching. Stand up straight.
背中 曲がってるぞ｡
しゃんと立て って…》
((お前 そんなことやってて
楽しいわけ？))
And you enjoy doing that?
《長谷川:母ちゃん… ｵﾚ…➡
Mom...am...I...standing up straight right now?
今 まっすぐ立てているか？》
...gawa...Hasegawa!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)長谷川～！ 長谷川～!!
今回の件は 父上に
報告させてもらうぞよ 長谷川!!
I'm going to tell my father about this, Hasegawa!
(長谷川)うるせえよ｡
はっ？
Shut up.
Shut up!
(長谷川)うるせえよ!!
なっ…!?
I said shut up you freakin' space flounder!
(長谷川)うるせえ って
言ってんだ このﾎﾟﾁﾀﾏ星人!!
♪♪～
≪あ～あ｡
いいのかな～？ んなことして～｡
Was it all right to do that?
知るか ﾊﾞｶﾀﾚ｡ ここは 侍の国だ｡
Good question, moron. This here is the land of the samurai.
好き勝手させるかってんだ｡
I can't just let them do anything they please.
でも もう 天人
取り締まれなくなりますよね？
But you won't be able to police the Amanto anymore.
間違いなく ﾘｽﾄﾗですよ｡
ﾊﾞｶだなぁ｡
You'll be canned for sure.
Boy you're dumb.
一時のﾃﾝｼｮﾝに 身を任せるﾔﾂは
身を滅ぼすんだよ｡
People who act on sheer impulse always ruin their lives.
(長谷川)えぇ～～っ!?
[Preview]
Gin, will you stop lying around and get up already?
Are you even motivated to do this show?
It's only been two months since the series started!
With the star of the show like this, we'll be cancelled before the end of the season!
The next episode: "There Is Butt A Fine Line Between Persistence And Stubbornness"
[Only two months into the show and the series' future is already in danger.]
[You think we should change the title character and start a show called "Shinsengumi Twenty-Four" next week?]
Hey, Gin?
Why is the title of this manga "Gin Tama"?
Because of the raunchy title, "Gin Tama,"
people have been complaining saying "we aren't allowed to buy the book."
From what I hear, it's part of the author's plot to make high-school girls throughout the country say things like,
"Hey, say, did you see this week's Gin Tama?"
He wanted to get it into the regular street talk.
Seems he failed miserably, though.
Well, that only seems right.
By the way, Kagura, what is that you've been eating?
Takoyaki!
[Pesu]
Yuck!
ねぇ 銀さん…｡
あ～ん？
このﾏﾝｶﾞ 何で 『銀魂』って
ﾀｲﾄﾙなんでしょうね｡
『銀魂』なんて
卑猥なﾀｲﾄﾙのせいで➡
単行本買えねえじゃねえか って
声が 続出してるそうですよ｡
なんでもね 空知って作者が
全国の女子高生に➡
｢ねぇねぇ 今週の『銀魂』観た？｣
みたいな ｽﾚｽﾚのｾﾘﾌはかせて➡
なんか ｱｯﾄﾎｰﾑな日本を作ろうと
企んでいたけど➡
大失敗だったらしいよ…｡
ﾌｰﾝ…｡ まぁ 当然ですね…｡
ところで 神楽ちゃん
さっきから 何食べてんの？
ﾀｺ焼き！
ぐぇっ…｡